

Marco Maida Computer scientist



13 August 1994



www.maida.me



mmaidacs@gmail.com

About me ———

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember.

I started working professionally as a developer in 2013. After three years, I started a bachelor degree in Computer Science, while I kept working part-time as game developer.

Once I graduated, I moved to Germany, and started a Joint Master and Ph.D. program. After completing my Master's program, publishing my first research paper, and doing an R&D internship in U.S., I decided to suspend my Ph.D. and return to industry.

Languages —

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am fluent in English,

und ich spreche etwas **Deutsch**.

Extras ——

I love camping and traveling with my bike: I often do the two together • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right • Striving not to be the smartest person in the room • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

Skills

I have more than nine years of professional experience. I extensively worked with **Python**, **C#**, **C++**, **C**, **Java**, **Rust** and **Coq** code. I have a mixed background of **industry** and **academia**.

I am comfortable working on **complex code bases** in large and small teams, and I quickly get used to new technologies. I can **analyze problems** and then design, implement, evaluate, document, and present my solutions.

I am very **outgoing** and I **love working in teams**. Due to my game development background, I am used to collaborating with different professional figures (e.g., artists, designers, musicians) and I have an eye for **user experience**.

Experience

2022 **R&D Intern.** Bloomberg LP - CTO I worked on accelerating SAT solving using GPUs (C++, CUDA).

2019-2022 **PhD Student.** Max Planck Institute

I studied timeliness certifications with formal verification (COQ) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux (C, Rust). I mentored

three interns and published three papers.

2016-2019 **Game developer.**

34BigThings

I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Switch, and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, dev tools and UIs.

2015-2016 Freelance Software Engineer.

Teoresi, Choralia, Maserati

I built an interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D (C#). I shipped on mobile devices and browsers (JS). I managed one artist I hired and collaborated with another engineer.

2013-2016 **Software engineer.**

R.O. 9

I developed software solutions for glass processing factories. I started as a developer (C, C++, C#, SQL) and later transitioned to planning new features and managing a small team (\leq 4 people).

Education

2019-2022 Master in Computer Science. Technische Universität Kaiserslautern

2016-2019 Bachelor in Computer Science. Università degli studi di Torino

2015-2016 **Game dev: Software Development** Event Horizon School.

Projects and Publications

2021 **Poet - Automatic Proof Generation.** Max Planck institute I developed a tool that yields a worst-case-scenario timing analysis of

software. The publication has received the *outstanding paper award* at ECRTS2022, a top-class conference for real-time systems.

(https://pure.mpg.de/rest/items/item_3391739_1/component/file_3391740/content)

2018 Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit. 34BigThings

I developed an open-source Unity3D framework that makes the creation of production-ready casual games extremely fast, paired by a Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the FMC games.

(www.github.com/340penThings)

2017 Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4. 34BigThings

I developed a framework that handles light effects on Razer's Chroma hardware that are coherent to what is happening in the game. This system is still used today in every 34BigThings game.

(www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)